

Satoko Gruson

Aspiring Bilingual Product Designer with experience in Project and Cross-functional Team Management

Volksgartenstr. 2 Munich 80639 GERMANY satokogruson@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/satokogruson

ABOUT ME

I am a bilingual professional with experience in legal and compliance-related project management within the pharmaceutical and biotech industry. I seek to combine the various skills and experience gained during my professional career with the technical UX/UI knowledge I have developed with CareerFoundry toward a product design and development management career.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Figma, Adobe Creative (Photoshop. Illustrator, Premier Pro, After Effects and XD)
- Program/Project planning & management
- Cross-functional team management
- Process implementation
- Power BI Analytics
- Primary and Secondary Research (legal and marketing)
- Translation & localization
- English and Japanese language fluency
- Intermediate level German (TELC Deutsch B2)
- Proficiency in Microsoft Office

CERTIFICATIONS

UI DESIGN PROGRAM

CareerFoundry
Scheduled completion April 2023

UX ACADEMY FOUNDATIONS

Designlab January 2022

STANFORD CERTIFIED PROJECT MANAGER (S.C.P.M)

Stanford University
Jan 2011

MAJOR ACHIEVEMENTS

UI/UX DESIGN

- Training in UI/UX Design fundamentals
 - Visual design fundamentals and UI /UX design principles
 - Competitive analysis, user research and interviews, user persona creation, IA task flows, wireframe, and prototype creation
 - Creation of style guides and responsive web and mobile landing pages using FIGMA
 - Logo creation and typography

Link to case study: UI Design Case Study

PROGRAM/PROJECT MANAGEMENT

- Successfully rolled out Corporate Compliance programs and projects, which included:
 - Defining the goals and objectives and preparing project charters
 - Managing internal and external stakeholders
 - Strategically guiding project members to ensure timely implementation
 - Leading employee research initiatives to identify needs and concerns to ensure smooth implementation of guidelines and policies through cross-functional teams
 - Continuous Communication and corrective actions as necessary
 - Organizing a company-wide training to ensure program goals were clear to the stakeholders
 - Planning and developing comprehensive and easy-to-learn e-learning programs
 - Regular reporting on progress and management of continuous improvement processes

RESEARCH AND DESIGN

- Conducted primary research on clients through Client Satisfaction surveys to address concerns and possible solutions/enhancements to financial products
- Secondary Research to evaluate pharmaceutical detailing effectiveness in various regions
- Redesigned intranet site for ease of accessibility to the relevant documentation
- Designed, produced, and supplied new financial services contracts through research of end-user behavior, leading to increased satisfaction levels among dealers

WORK HISTORY

FREELANCER

Caster Biz Co. Ltd.

December 2022 - Present

SENIOR ASSOCIATE COMPLIANCE

Amgen K.K.

April 2019- December 2020

SITE CONTRACT LEADER

Paraxel International Inc.

November 2018 – March 2019

SENIOR PARALEGAL

Illumina Japan November 2017 – October 2018

LEGAL OPERATIONS

Boehringer Ingelheim Japan Inc. August 2007 - May 2011

MARKETING RESEARCH

Boehringer Ingelheim Japan Inc. November 2004 – July 2007

SALES & MARKETING ANALYST

Primus Financial Services November 2001 - July 2004

DOCUMENTATION & SETTLEMENTS OFFICER

Australia and New Zealand Banking Group Ltd July 2000 - June 2001

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

MASTER OF ARTS IN TRANSLATION & LOCALIZATION MANAGEMENT

Middlebury Institute of International Studies August 2020 – May 2022 GPA 3.97

Major Projects include:

- Design in Internationalization
- Software localization (mainly C#)
- Website creation and translation using WordPress
- DTP translation and editing using Adobe Photoshop/InDesign
- Audio editing and text/subtitle editing using Adobe Audition and Premiere Pro

GRADUATE DIPLOMA OF LAW

BPP Law School September 2008 – November 2010

CERTIFICATE OF INTERNATIONAL LAW

Beasley School of Law at Temple University September 2007 - August 2008

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS/HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT

RMIT University April 1995 - October 1999

- Minor in Marketing